Nguyen Minh Trung

Software Developer

Tel: (+84) 773434560

Email/Skype: trungnm0512@qmail.com

Have been working in the software development field for more than 3.5 years. My goal is to become a Solution Architect, focusing on the technical side of product development.

Experienced in all the stages of product development life cycle, having ability to work effectively independently or with a team.

EXPERIENCE

Kiu House - Founder and Operation manager

Sep 2017 - Jun 2020

Built and operated one of the first short-term rental chains on Airbnb in Danang. Managed booking, stay and communication with foreign visitors

eDoctor, HCMC - Backend Developer

Sep 2016 - May 2017

eDoctor is the leading online health care application in Vietnam, with over 15000 users and 100.000 health checks, my main responsibility was converting the whole database from RethinkDB into MongoDB and developing new features.

- Studied database (rethinkDB), wrote script to extract database schema
- Built Mongoose schema
- Updated code base to reflect new changes
- Manual tested new code
- Implemented new features

Stack:

RethinkDB, MongoDB/Mongoose, NodeJS, Hapi, Git

NRH VietNam, HCMC - Developer

Nov 2015 - Sep 2016

Was solely responsible for developing Fideli Loyalty system that helps customers to create their own loyalty programs .

- Studied new technologies and concepts
- Fully in charge of designing, developing and integrating solutions

- Designed, documented APIs for third party system (Swagger)
- Developed front-end interface for customer management system
- Automated Unit test (MochaJs) / API test (Postman test suites)

Stack:

- NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB/Mongoose, Redis
- HTML, CSS, Jquery, Bootstrap framework
- ReSTful API, Microservices, Docker, Git
- Event sourcing CQRS
- MQTT Mosquitto broker

FPT Software, Da Nang - Java Developer

Jan 2015 - Nov 2015

Analyzed user requirements, created documents, coded, tested for a Wedding planning system. In charge of a separate module - writing review for wedding.

- Tracked and fixed bugs or defects through issue & project tracking tools like JIRA
- Evaluated business constraints and requirements of existed Web-based system to upgrade; converted and built back-end services with optimal performance
- Reviewed issues and proposed solutions in a daily meeting

Stack: Java, r2 framework, OracleDB, HTML, CSS, JS

Achievement: Excellent employee S1 - 2015

FPT Software, Da Nang - Java Developer (Intern)

Jan 2013 - Apr 2013

Developed an official Java-based online quiz system for the Corporate Training Center (CTC) of FPT Software Co. Ltd - Da Nang.

Stack: Java, Struts 2, OracleDB, HTML, CSS, JS

CERTIFICATION / PROJECTS

• AWS Certified Solution Architect - Associate (issued Nov 2020)

EDUCATION

FPT University - Bachelor of Software Engineering - 2015

GITHUB

MeoBeol/Catify - utility for Spotify (Awesome list / 58 stars)

NodeJs / Electron / ReactJS / Material-UI / TravisCI